hi i'm attorney gregory dell with the
law firm of attorneys down shaffer and i
want to speak to you about a recent case
that took place against the prudential
disability insurance company now this
wasn't a case that was handled by our
firm
but the important thing in this case is
that this was a case that was handled by
a colorado attorney who
obviously appears to have not been an
experienced disability attorney
and i want to give you some examples of
you know what a court had to say in this
particular case and what can happen
if you happen to retain a lawyer who
thinks that they know erisa disability
law
but they really don't so it's super
important that you hire a law firm
that's handled hundreds if not thousands
of erisa disability claims and knows all
the intricacies of this complicated
federal law
now in this particular case it was a
very simple and routine request that
came down from prudential after the
lawsuit was filed prudential basically
asked the
plaintiff the claimant's lawyer to have
his client sign
a medical hipaa authorization
so that prudential could release medical
records to the court as part of the
administrative record now this is an
obvious routine thing the court has to
be able to review medical records but in
many cases prudential doesn't want to
disclose any medical information that
they shouldn't
so they ask the claimant to sign a hipaa
which is a medical authorization
authorizing the court to be able to
review the records
well the plaintiff's attorney in this
case refused to allow
the claimant to sign the medical
authorization then prudential had to
file a motion and a subpoena asking for
the claimant to sign this medical
authorization the planner's attorney at
that time didn't object and said okay
the claimant will sign the authorization
well prudential thought that this was an
utter waste of time and something was
unnecessary and filed a motion for
sanctions against the claimant and the
claimant's attorney and what the court
ended up saying was that your conduct
was the plaintiff attorney's conduct was
vexatious and unreasonable and beyond
the standard of what should be normal
for an experienced disability attorney
and the court went as far as to say in
their opinion that this attorney who was
handling this erisa claim was an
inexperienced attorney
prudential asked for sanctions against
the
claimant's attorney because of the fact
that the
the prudential attorneys had to spend a
lot of time just to get a medical
release now there's a couple things that
happened
number one
the court ordered the plaintiff's
attorney not the claimant to pay four
thousand dollars in attorney's fees to
prudential which is unfortunate number
two
this plaintiff's attorney who was
representing the claimant ended up
really just
making the court mad and there's one
thing you want to do you don't want to
use the word you don't want to disturb a
judge or make the judge mad because the
judge is the one who's going to make the
ultimate decision on your claim so you
put a bad taste in the mouth of the
judge and now the judge is unfortunately
as a human being is going to hold that
against the claimant
there were other things that this
plaintiff's attorney did the plaintiff's
attorney demanded a jury trial the plans
attorney initially filed the case in
state court all things that show a level
of inexperience and when you have an
attorney that's not experienced
there's no way that the court is going
to give the claim the respect that it's
due there's no way that the court is
going to respect the plaintiff's counsel
and the claimant because they're
frustrated
so if you have a claim
obviously hire the lawyer with the most
possible experience ask your lawyer
about their track record ask them to
provide you with client references of
what they've done
these are all things that we have
available we're ready willing and able
to give you what we'd like to do is if
you have a claim whether it's against
prudential or any other carrier whether
it's a lawsuit an appeal an application
no matter where you're located in the
country
we always offer a free consultation and
we look forward to the opportunity to
review your file and let you know how we
can work with you to get you the
benefits that you're entitled to